Leonard Everett Fisher Papers
© 2010 University of Connecticut
Leonard Everett Fisher Papers.
1927-1999.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Fisher, Leonard Everett.
14.5 linear feet.
The collection includes notes, early drafts, both edited and unedited manuscripts, press proofs, galleys, page layouts, dummies, art work (sketches, scratchboard, acrylic, etc.), and correspondence with his editors and publishing companies for over fifty titles.
MSS19970064
Biography
Leonard Everett Fisher, the well-known author and illustrator, was born in Bronx, New York, in 1924. Although his father was a ship designer by trade, he was also an aspiring artist. Through the influence of his father, Mr. Fisher learned of his own skills at an early age. By the time he was in second grade, he was already winning awards for his artwork. After serving in World War II as a cartographer, he attended Yale University's School of Art where he received his Bachelors and Masters degrees in Fine Arts. His first published book illustration was the book jacket for The Silken Secret, published in 1954. His first illustrated book, The Exploits of Xenophon, was published by Random House in 1955. Fisher's work covers a broad range, as he writes history, science, biographies, science fiction, legends, and poetry. Mr. Fisher has been honored with such awards as the Joseph Pulitzer Painting Fellowship, the William Wirt Winchester Traveling Fellowship, the Premio Grafico Fiera di Bologna, the 1981 National Jewish Book Award for Children's Literature, and the Christopher Medal, along with numerous others for his painting, writing and illustrating skills. In addition to authoring over eighty books, and illustrating more than two hundred and sixty, Mr. Fisher has also designed ten United States Postage stamps.
Mr. Fisher currently resides in Westport, Connecticut with his wife Margery. He has three grown children and six grandchildren who were often the inspiration for his books. Although he is well known and admired for his scratchboard drawings and his acrylic paintings, he also uses other media.
Some of Leonard Everett Fisher's books include The Great Wall of China, Gandhi, The Seven Days of Creation, The White House, and his more recent Cyclops, and Alexander Graham Bell (1999). Currently he is working on a new book, entitled The Gods and Goddesses of the Ancient Maya.
Scope and Content
The collection includes notes, early drafts, both edited and unedited manuscripts, press proofs, galleys, page layouts, dummies, art work (sketches, scratchboard, acrylic, etc.), and correspondence with his editors and publishing companies. Book titles are listed in the following pages. There are also videotapes and audiocassettes of appearances and interviews conducted with the author.
Organization
Series I: Books authored/illustrated by LEF (undated, 1927-1999).
Series II: Scrapbooks, Kidstamps & printing blocks listing.
Series III: Filmstrips created by LEF- artwork.
Series IV: Audiovisual materials.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a significant collection of children's literature and related artwork. Contact the Curator for further information.
Bibliography
Something About the Author. Detroit: Gale; Anne Commire; 1983; pp.87-97, vol. 34.
"Leonard Fisher: A Giant among Authors." The Chronicle [Willimantic, CT], Nov. 12, 1998; B6-B7.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
Donated to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center by Leonard Everett Fisher and his wife, Margery Meskin Fisher over a period of years ranging from August 1989 - the present.
Accruals
Additions to the collection have been received but are not yet processed and are, therefore, not represented in the finding aid. Please contact the Curator for Children's Literature for further information.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Books Illustrated and/or Authored by Leonard Everett Fisher ,undated, 1927-1999
  - Galileo, 1992
    - Research Notes, undated (Box 1:1)
    - Proposals, 1990 (Box 1:2)
    - Manuscript (edited), 1991 May 1 (Box 1:3)
    - Manuscript (edited), 1991 May 22 (Box 1:4)
    - Manuscript, 1991 May 23 (Box 1:5)
    - Manuscript (edited), 1991 July 12 (Box 1:6)
    - Manuscript (edited with production notes), 1991 July 12 (Box 1:7)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 1:8)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 1:9)
    - Dummy without art, undated (Box 1:10)
    - Art work, undated (Box 1:11)
    - Dust jackets, undated (Box 1:12)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1:13)
    - Photo dummy- text (17 pages), undated (Box 20:695)
  - Marie Curie, 1994
    - Notes, undated (Box 1:14)
    - Manuscript, 1993 May 26 (Box 1:15)
    - Manuscript, 1993 May 27 (Box 1:16)
    - Manuscript, 1993 August 20 (Box 1:17)
    - Manuscript (printed from disk), undated (Box 1:18)
    - Galley I, 1993 October 18 (Box 1:19)
    - Galley II, undated (Box 1:20)
    - Galley II, undated (Box 1:21)
    - Photo dummy (17 pages -no even pages), undated (Box 20:694)
  - Pyramid of the Sun, Pyramid of the Moon, 1988
    - Notes, undated (Box 1:22)
    - Proposal, undated (Box 1:23)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 1:24)
    - Timeline of Mexican Civilization, undated (Box 1:25)
    - Page layout notes, undated (Box 1:26)
    - Manuscript, 1987 June 6 (Box 1:27)
    - Manuscript (edited by Dr. Blanton), undated (Box 1:28)
    - Manuscript, 1987 June 10 (Box 1:29)
    - Manuscript, 1987 August (Box 1:30)
    - Manuscript, 1987 August 3 (Box 1:31)
    - Manuscript, 1987 October 20 (Box 1:32)
    - Font Samples, undated (Box 1:33)
    - Proof, undated (Box 1:34)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 1:35)
    - Jacket proof, undated (Box 1:36)
    - Page proofs, undated (Box 1:37)
    - Printer's dummy, undated (Box 1:38)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 1:39)
    - Acrylic illustrations (8 items), 1988 (Box 20:688A)
    - Art work- original figures (9 items), 1988 (Box 20:688)
    - Art work- photocopied figures (2 sheets), 1988 (Box 20:689)
    - Photo dummy-text (pp.2-3, 6-31), undated (Box 20:690)
    - Photo proof artwork (pp.1-31, cover & extra 20,21), undated (Box 20:691)
    - Photo dummy of jacket, undated (Box 20:692)
    - Jacket, undated (Box 20:693)
  - The Tower of London, 1988
    - Notes, undated (Box 2:40)
    - Book plan / proposal, undated (Box 2:41)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:42)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:43)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:44)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:45)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:46)
    - Galley (edited), 1986 February 13 (Box 2:47)
    - Galley proof, 1986 February 13 (Box 2:48)
    - Text sample, 1986 February 27 (Box 2:49)
    - Manuscript and type sample, 1986 November 12 (Box 2:50)
    - Galley (edited), 1986 November 12 (Box 2:51)
    - Galley proof (edited), 1986 November 12 (Box 2:52)
    - Galley proof (edited), style sheet, 1986 November 12 (Box 2:53)
    - Galley, 1987 March 4 (Box 2:54)
    - Map text and flap text, undated (Box 2:55)
    - Galley map text, 1987 February 13 (Box 2:56)
    - Flap text specifications, undated (Box 2:57)
    - Title- reproduction original, undated (Box 2:58)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 2:59)
    - Art work and photomechanicals, undated (Box 2:60)
    - Book binding specifications, undated (Box 2:61)
    - Jacket proof, undated (Box 2:62)
    - Book mock-up, undated (Box 2:63)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 2:64)
    - Acrylic illustrations (7), 1987 (Box 48:1431)
  - Sailboat Lost, 1991
    - Notes, undated (Box 1:65)
    - Proposal #1, undated (Box 1:66)
    - Proposal #2, undated (Box 2:67)
    - Manuscript, 1990 August 3 (Box 2:68)
    - Manuscript, 1990 August 7 (Box 2:69)
    - Manuscript, 1990 August 12 (Box 2:70)
    - Font samples, undated (Box 2:71)
    - Proof, undated (Box 2:72)
    - Proof, 1990 November 13 (Box 2:73)
    - LCC information, undated (Box 2:74)
    - Book Jacket Specifications, undated (Box 2:75A)
    - Jacket text and layout, undated (Box 2:75)
    - Photos and negatives, undated (Box 2:76)
    - Unused painting, undated (Box 2:77)
    - Cover proposals, undated (Box 2:78)
    - Press proof (uncut), undated (Box 2:79)
    - Printer's dummy (press proof), undated (Box 2:80)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 2:81)
    - Photo overlays, undated (Box 53:1462)
  - Oregon Trail, 1991
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:82)
    - Manuscript (Box 2:83)
    - Manuscript map details, undated (Box 2:84)
    - Editorial changes / Correspondence, undated (Box 2:85)
    - Edited Manuscript, undated (Box 2:86)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:87)
    - Proof-caption credits (Box 2:88)
    - Book dummy, undated (Box 2:89)
    - Book mock-up, undated (Box 2:90)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 2:91)
    - Proofs, 1990 February 27 (Box 20:683)
    - Galley, 1990 April 26 (Box 20:684)
    - Galley (incomplete), 1990 May 2 (Box 20:685)
    - Map, 1990 (Box 20:686)
    - Map, 1990 (Box 20:687)
  - Ghandi, 1996
    - Notes, undated (Box 3:92)
    - Proposal, 1993 September (Box 3:93)
    - Proposal, 1995 February (Box 3:94)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), undated (Box 3:95)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 3:96)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 3:97)
    - Manuscript (edited), 1994 November 3 (Box 3:98)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), undated (Box 3:99)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 3:100)
    - Font samples, undated (Box 3:101)
    - Proof, undated (Box 3:102)
    - Map Plan, undated (Box 3:103)
    - Proofs- map text, undated (Box 3:104)
    - Cover dummy, undated (Box 3:105)
    - Photocopy- book mock up, undated (Box 3:106)
    - Book mock-up, undated (Box 3:107)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 3:108)
  - William Tell, 1996
    - Research, undated (Box 3:109)
    - Proposal, undated (Box 3:110)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 3:111)
    - Manuscript, 1994 August 11 (Box 3:112)
    - Manuscript (edited), 1994 October 31 (Box 3:113)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 3:114)
    - Text overlay, undated (Box 3:115)
    - Text sample, undated (Box 3:116)
    - Galley, undated (Box 3:117)
    - Printer's proofs and editor's notes, undated (Box 3:118)
    - Font proofs, undated (Box 3:119)
    - Jacket sketch, undated (Box 3:120)
    - Jacket and frontis piece proofs, undated (Box 3:121)
    - Jacket print (poor quality), undated (Box 3:122)
    - Jacket proof and binding suggestion, undated (Box 3:123)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 3:124)
    - Press proof, cut, undated (Box 19:663)
    - Press proof, cut, undated (Box 19:664)
    - Photocopied F & G, 1996 (Box 19:665)
  - Gutenberg, 1993
    - Art work, 1943 (Box 4:125)
    - Book plan, Timeline, 1992 April 7 (Box 4:126)
    - Manuscript, 1992 April 23 (Box 4:127)
    - Manuscript, 1992 July 21 (Box 4:128)
    - Manuscript- editor's notes, 1992 July 21 (Box 4:129)
    - Photocopies and Permission for Gutenberg's Bible, undated (Box 4:130)
    - Fax from lithographer, 1993 March 1 (Box 4:131)
    - Manuscript, 1992 September 18 (Box 4:132)
    - Galley, undated (Box 4:133)
    - Galley, undated (Box 4:134)
    - Expert's comments, undated (Box 4:135)
    - Galley-editor's notes to printer, undated (Box 4:136)
    - Galley, undated (Box 4:137)
    - Galley (edited), undated (Box 4:138)
    - Galley, undated (Box 4:139)
    - Galley, 1st revision, undated (Box 4:140)
    - Galley, 2nd revision, 1992 October 12 (Box 4:141)
    - Galley, 3rd revision, undated (Box 4:142)
    - Text samples, color swatch, undated (Box 4:143)
    - Flap text notes, undated (Box 4:143A)
    - Proof- jacket text, undated (Box 4:144A)
    - Jacket text- printer's proof, undated (Box 4:144)
    - Art work, undated (Box 4:145)
    - Photo of artwork, undated (Box 4:146A)
    - Cover and frontisdummy, undated (Box 4:146)
    - Title page, art-work & lettering, undated (Box 4:147A)
    - Title page, undated (Box 4:147)
    - Printer's dummy, undated (Box 4:148)
    - Printer's dummy, undated (Box 4:149)
    - Correspondence re: French version, undated (Box 4:150)
    - Fed-ex slips, letter receipts, undated (Box 4:151)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 4:152)
    - Title page paste-up, 1993 (Box 48:1427)
    - Text match print, 1993 (Box 48:1428)
    - Printer's mock-up, 1993 (Box 48:1429)
    - Photo overlays, undated (Box 48:1430)
  - The Wailing Wall, 1989
    - Research, undated (Box 4:153)
    - Proposal, 1989 (Box 4:154)
    - Manuscript, 1989 (Box 4:155)
    - Manuscript, 1989 (Box 4:156)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:157)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:158)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:159)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:160)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:161)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:162)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:163)
    - Printing specifications, font samples, undated (Box 4:164)
    - Dust jacket, undated (Box 4:165)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 4:166)
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 19:661)
    - Acrylic illustrations (7 items), undated (Box 19:662Z)
  - The Great Wall of China, 1986
    - Plan, undated (Box 5:167)
    - Notes, undated (Box 5:168)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 5:169)
    - Early Illustrations, undated (Box 5:170)
    - Wood block print, undated (Box 5:171)
    - Characters, undated (Box 5:172)
    - Jacket illustrations, undated (Box 5:173)
    - Press proof, undated (Box 5:174)
    - First draft, undated (Box 5:174A)
    - Second draft, undated (Box 5:174B)
    - Third draft, undated (Box 5:174C)
    - Fourth draft, undated (Box 5:174D)
    - Final draft, 1986 (Box 5:174E)
    - Transfer receipts, 1985-1986 (Box 5:175)
    - Page layout (pp. 1-3,6-32 & jacket), undated (Box 20:677)
    - Page layout, undated (Box 20:677A)
    - Book layout (15 pages), undated (Box 20:678)
  - Prince Henry the Navigator, 1990
    - Book proposal, undated (Box 5:176)
    - Book proposal, undated (Box 5:177)
    - Book proposal, undated (Box 5:178)
    - Book plan, undated (Box 5:179)
    - Notes, undated (Box 5:180)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), undated (Box 5:181)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), 1989 April 18 (Box 5:182)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), undated (Box 5:183)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), undated (Box 5:184)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 5:185)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 5:186)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 5:187)
    - Font samples, undated (Box 5:188)
    - Proof pages, undated (Box 5:189)
    - Unedited text blocks, undated (Box 5:190)
    - Jacket sample, undated (Box 5:191)
    - Jacket proof, undated (Box 5:192)
    - Book mock-up with jacket, undated (Box 5:193)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 5:194)
    - Artwork (2 items), undated (Box 20:679)
    - Acrylic illustrations (5), undated (Box 20:679A)
    - Jacket mechanical (7 items), undated (Box 20:680)
    - Printers proof & art work (21 items), undated (Box 20:681)
    - Early page layouts (4 items and 13 stapled others), undated (Box 20:682)
  - Tracks Across America, 1992
    - Research for maps, undated (Box 6:195)
    - Editor's comments on manuscript, undated (Box 6:196)
    - Manuscript (edited), undated (Box 6:197)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 6:198)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 6:199)
    - Manuscript (edited), undated (Box 6:200)
    - Manuscript (edited), undated (Box 6:201)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 6:202)
    - Captions/ Sources, undated (Box 6:203)
    - Captions, labels, undated (Box 6:204)
    - Photocopies, undated (Box 6:205)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 6:206)
    - Proof, undated (Box 6:207)
    - Galley proof, undated (Box 6:208)
    - Label, galley proofs, undated (Box 6:209)
    - Proof for captions and cover, undated (Box 6:210)
    - Corrections/ Proofs, undated (Box 6:211)
    - Edited proofs, undated (Box 6:212)
    - Changes, notes, undated (Box 6:213)
    - Flap text, undated (Box 6:214)
    - Jacket, flap text, undated (Box 6:215)
    - Pamphlet, undated (Box 6:216)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 6:217)
    - Advertising page, undated (Box 6:217A)
  - Theseus and the Minotaur, 1989
    - Notes, undated (Box 6:218)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), 1987 (Box 6:219)
    - Manuscript (incomplete), 1987 (Box 6:220)
    - Bibliography, 1987 December 15 (Box 6:221)
    - Author's proof, undated (Box 6:222)
    - Manuscript with printing notes, 1988 (Box 6:223)
    - Manuscript (edited), 1988 (Box 6:224)
    - Proof, undated (Box 6:225)
    - Proof, 1988 March 11 (Box 6:226)
    - Proof text (cut), undated (Box 6:227)
    - Jacket text, undated (Box 6:228)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 7:229)
    - Acrylic illustrations (3), 1988 (Box 48:1433)
  - Storm at the Jetty, 1981
    - Book notes, plans, undated (Box 7:230)
    - Book proposal, 1977 August 15 (Box 7:231)
    - Editor's comments, 1979-1980 (Box 7:232)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 7:233)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 7:234)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 7:235)
    - Illustrations, drafts, undated (Box 7:236)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 7:237)
    - Jacket plan, undated (Box 7:238)
    - Cover, photocopy, undated (Box 7:239)
    - Art work, sample, 1980 May 5 (Box 7:240)
    - Photograph of painting used in book, ca. 1982 (Box 7:241A)
    - Uncut press proofs, undated (Box 7:241)
    - Cut press proofs, undated (Box 7:242)
    - Cut press proofs, undated (Box 7:243)
    - Unbound book, 1981 (Box 7:244A)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 7:244)
  - David and Goliath, 1993
    - Bible text photocopy, undated (Box 7:245)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 7:246)
    - Book plan, undated (Box 7:247)
    - Manuscript, 1992 April 6 (Box 7:248)
    - Manuscript, 1992 April 6 (Box 7:249)
    - Manuscript, 1992 May 30 (Box 7:250)
    - Manuscript, 1992 May 19 (Box 7:251)
    - Manuscript, 1992 June 2 (Box 7:252)
    - Manuscript, 1992 June 10 (Box 7:253)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 7:254)
    - Fax, re: flap text, 1992 August 26 (Box 7:255)
    - Fax, re: cover proof, 1992 September 21 (Box 7:256)
    - Paste up dummy, undated (Box 7:257)
    - Page proof, undated (Box 7:258)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 7:259)
    - Acrylic illustrations (6 items), 1993 (Box 19:662)
  - Colonial Craftsmen Series 1
    - 12 prints of illustrations for series, undated (Box 8:260A)
    - The Glassmakers, 1964
      - Book Plan, undated (Box 8:260)
      - Book Plan, undated (Box 8:261)
      - Glossary, undated (Box 8:262)
      - Outline, undated (Box 8:163)
      - Manuscript, first draft, undated (Box 8:264)
      - Manuscript, second draft, undated (Box 8:265)
      - Illustration, undated (Box 8:266)
      - Dust jacket plans, undated (Box 8:267)
      - Color swatches, undated (Box 8:268)
      - Press proof, undated (Box 8:269)
      - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 8:270)
    - The Silversmiths, 1964
      - Research, undated (Box 8:271)
      - Manuscript, first draft, undated (Box 8:272)
      - Manuscript, second draft, undated (Box 8:273)
      - Manuscript, third draft, undated (Box 8:274)
      - Manuscript, fourth draft, undated (Box 8:275)
    - The Papermakers, 1965
      - Draft and research notes, undated (Box 8:276)
      - Draft and research notes, undated (Box 8:277)
    - The Printers, 1965
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8:278)
    - The Wigmakers, 1965
      - Research and notes, undated (Box 8:279)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8:280)
      - Book plan, undated (Box 8:281)
      - Press proof, flap text, undated (Box 8:282)
      - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 8:283)
      - Matted & signed piece of the first draft, 1965 (Box 52:1454)
      - Scratchboard illustrations, 1965 (Box 52:1455)
    - The Hatters, 1965
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8:284)
      - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 8:285)
      - Book Plan, undated (Box 8:286)
    - The Tanners, 1966
      - Manuscript, carbon copy (incomplete), undated (Box 8:287)
      - Manuscript, draft (incomplete), undated (Box 8:288)
      - Cut Proof, undated (Box 8:288B)
    - The Weavers, 1966
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8:289)
    - The Cabinetmakers, 1966
      - Manuscript draft, "A Short History", undated (Box 8:290)
      - Manuscript, "A Short History", undated (Box 8:291)
      - Manuscript draft, "How the Cabinetmakers Worked", undated (Box 8:292)
      - Manuscript draft, list of American cabinetmakers, undated (Box 8:293)
    - The Shoemakers, 1967
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8:294)
    - The Schoolmasters, 1967
      - Drafts, page 1, undated (Box 8:295)
      - Drafts, page 2, undated (Box 8:296)
      - Drafts, page 3, undated (Box 8:297)
      - Drafts, page 4, undated (Box 8:298)
      - Drafts, page 5, undated (Box 8:299)
      - Drafts, page 6, undated (Box 8:300)
      - Drafts, page 7, undated (Box 8:301)
      - Drafts, page 9, undated (Box 8:302)
      - Drafts, page 10, undated (Box 8:303)
      - Drafts, page 10, undated (Box 8:304)
      - Drafts, page 12, undated (Box 8:305)
      - Drafts, page 13, undated (Box 8:306)
      - Proof, undated (Box 8:307A)
    - The Peddlers, 1968
      - Manuscript draft, undated (Box 8:307)
    - Doctors, 1968
      - Book plan, undated (Box 8:308)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8:309)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 8:310)
      - Manuscript, carbon copy, undated (Box 8:311)
      - List of doctors, undated (Box 8:312)
      - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 8:313)
  - Colonial Craftsmen Series II
    - The Potters, 1969
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 9:314)
    - The Limners, 1969
      - Research, undated (Box 9:315)
      - Book Plan/ Notes, undated (Box 9:316)
      - Book Plan/ Notes, undated (Box 9:317)
      - Manuscript, page 1, undated (Box 9:318)
      - Manuscript, page 2, undated (Box 9:319)
      - Manuscript, page 3, undated (Box 9:320)
      - Manuscript, page 4, undated (Box 9:321)
      - Manuscript, page 5, undated (Box 9:322)
      - Manuscript, page 6, undated (Box 9:323)
      - Manuscript, page 7, undated (Box 9:324)
      - Manuscript, page 8, undated (Box 9:325)
      - Manuscript, page 9, undated (Box 9:326)
      - Manuscript, page 10, undated (Box 9:327)
      - Manuscript, page 11, undated (Box 9:328)
      - Manuscript, page 12, undated (Box 9:329)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 9:330)
      - List of paintings, undated (Box 9:331)
    - The Architects, 1970
      - Notes, undated (Box 9:332)
      - Photographic choices, undated (Box 9:333)
      - Book plan, undated (Box 9:334)
      - Title page draft, undated (Box 9:335)
      - Drafts, page 1, undated (Box 9:336)
      - Drafts, page 2, undated (Box 9:337)
      - Drafts, page 3, undated (Box 9:338)
      - Drafts, page 4, undated (Box 9:339)
      - Drafts, page 5, undated (Box 9:340)
      - Drafts, page 6, undated (Box 9:341)
      - Drafts, page 7, undated (Box 9:342)
      - Drafts, page 8, undated (Box 9:343)
      - Drafts, page 9, undated (Box 9:344)
      - Drafts, page 10, undated (Box 9:345)
      - Drafts, page 11, undated (Box 9:346)
      - Drafts, page 12, undated (Box 9:347)
      - Drafts, page 13, undated (Box 9:348)
      - Drafts, page 14, undated (Box 9:349)
      - Manuscript (edited), 1970 (Box 9:350)
    - The Shipbuilders, 1971
      - Notes, Drafts, undated (Box 9:351)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 9:352)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 9:353)
      - Manuscript, carbon copy, undated (Box 9:354)
    - The Homemakers, 1973
      - Manuscript draft, introduction, undated (Box 9:355)
      - Draft, notes, "Candlemaking", undated (Box 9:356)
      - Draft, notes, "Soapmaking", undated (Box 9:357)
      - Draft, notes, "Broommaking", undated (Box 9:358)
      - Draft, notes, "Cidermaking", undated (Box 9:359)
      - Manuscript (incomplete), undated (Box 9:360)
      - Photocopy of manuscript, 1973 (Box 9:361)
    - The Blacksmiths, 1976
      - Research Notes, undated (Box 9:362)
      - Manuscript, page 1, undated (Box 9:363)
      - Manuscript, page 2, undated (Box 9:364)
      - Manuscript, page 3, undated (Box 9:365)
      - Manuscript, page 4, undated (Box 9:366)
      - Manuscript, page 5, undated (Box 9:367)
      - Manuscript, page 6, undated (Box 9:368)